Register of the Robert F. Turner Papers, 1958-1975
Hoover Institution Archives
Robert F. Turner Papers
1958-1975
74040
Hoover Institution Archives
52 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box, 1 card file box, 17 envelopes, 1 album box, 1 phonotape cassette, 1 phonorecord (25.2 linear feet)
Correspondence, writings, reports, speeches, press releases, clippings, printed matter, sound recordings, photographs, and memorabilia, relating to political, social and cultural conditions in Vietnam and to the Vietnamese War
Turner, Robert F.
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1974.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Abbreviations
ARVN Army of the Republic of Vietnam
COSVN Central Office for South Vietnam. Communist Command of the Forces in South Vietnam
JUSPAO Joint U.S. Public Affairs Office, Saigon
MACV Military Advisory Command Vietnam
MIA Missing in Action
ML Mission in Charge of Liaison
MRC Military Revolutionary Council
NFL SVN founded in 1960 (to struggle in order to oppose the RVN administration and the U.S., and to progress toward neutrality and reunification with the North)
NLF National Front for Liberation
NVA North Vietnamese Army
PAVN Peoples Army of the Republic of Vietnam
PNF Patriotic Neutralist Forces (Laos)
PRP People's Revolutionary Party
PRYL People's Revolutionary Party Youth League
PSYOPS Psychological Operations
Quoc Dan Dang Nationalist Party
Armed Forces of Vietnam
RF Regional Forces in South Vietnam
PF Popular Forces in South Vietnam
SEATO Southeast Asia Treaty Organization
Tet Contraction of Nguyen Dan Tiet, meaning Festival of the first day of the year. Chinese in origin, the holiday symbolizes the beginning of the Oriental New Year (Lunar New Year)
USAID U.S. Agency for International Development
USIA U.S. Information Agency
USOM Unites States Operations Mission
VC Administration Machinery in South Vietnam:
(COSVN) 1. The Central Office of South Vietnam
(PRP) 2. The Vietnam People's Revolutionary Party
(NFLSV) 3. The National Front for the Liberation of South Vietnam
VCI Viet Cong Infrastructure
VIVA Victory in Vietnam Association; a nationwide student organization, since 1967 in Los Angeles, and supporting our government and our military
VNQDD Vietnam Quoc Dan Dang (Vietnam Nationalist Party)
VWP Vietnam Workers' Party
YICA Yearbook on International Communist Affairs
United States. Army; United States. Embassy (Vietnam); Asia, Southeastern.; Phonorecords.; Phonotapes.; United States--Armed Forces.; United States--Foreign relations--Vietnam.; United States--Foreign relations.; Vietnam War, 1961-1975.; Vietnam--Foreign relations--United States.; Vietnam--Politics and government.; Vietnam.
- Writings. (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  Manuscript of a projected book on Vietnamese communism, by R. F. Turner as well as published and unpublished articles, speeches, and reports.
- Subject File, 1963-1972. (Box 2. - 32.)
  Reports, memoranda, articles transcripts of interviews, notes, pamphlets, clippings, and printed matter relating to Vietnam; collected by R. F. Turner, and arranged alphabetically.
- Miscellany. (Box 32)
  Clippings.
- Photographs. (Box Envelopes A-U)
- Increment, December 1977. (Box 33. - 39.)
- Writings.
  - Manuscript to a projected book on Vietnamese communism, by R. F. Turner. (Box 1)
- Subject File, 1963-1972.
  - Agriculture in the Democratic Republic of Vietnam (DRV) (North Vietnam) (Box 2)
  - Agriculture in South Vietnam (SVN)
  - Albania
  - Alliance of National Democratic and Peace Forces
  - American Friends of Vietnam
  - Anti-Americanism in Vietnam
  - Army of the Republic of Vietnam (ARVN)
    - Regional and Popular Forces in South Vietnam (RF & PF).
    - Desertions
    - Viet Cong (VC), infiltration of
  - Art and architecture
  - Asian opinion on United States involvement in Cambodia
  - Assassination
  - Attitudes, Vietnam
  - Background information on South Vietnam (Box 3)
  - Black market in North Vietnam
  - Bloodbath argument
  - Bombing
  - Buddhism in Vietnam
  - Bulgaria
  - Cambodia
    - General (Box 4)
    - 1970
    - 1971
    - Miscellaneous
  - Captured documents (VC/NVA) (U.S. Mission Press Releases)
  - Casualties, Vietnam
  - Cease fires
  - Cease fires in Vietnam War
  - Center for Vietnamese Studies (Southern Illinois University) (Box 5)
  - Chemical warfare in Vietnam
  - Children, use of by VC
  - Chieu Hoi
  - Chieu Hoi Program
  - China
  - China (Box 6)
  - China and North Vietnam
  - Chinese advisors (VC)
  - Chronology, Vietnam
  - Chronology, Vietnam (Box 7)
  - Citizens Committee for Peace With Freedom in Vietnam
  - Civic Action
  - Coalition government
  - Coalition government, VC position
  - Communication
  - Communication (Box 8)
  - Constitution, Republic of Vietnam (RVN)
  - Corruption in South Vietnam
  - Cost of Vietnam War to U.S.
  - Counter-insurgency operations
  - Coup d'Etat
  - Cuba
  - Culture, Vietnam
  - Czechoslovakia
  - Dalat, Vietnam, general information
  - Dien Bien Phu, (1954)
  - Defectors and returnees
  - East Germany (Box 9)
  - Economic conditions, Vietnam
  - Economy of South Vietnam
  - Education
  - Education in South Vietnam (Box 10)
  - Elections in South Vietnam
    - General information
    - Pre-1967
    - 1967
    - 1970
    - 1971
    - VC position on and response to
  - Elections in North Vietnam
  - Ethnic minorities
  - External aid (DRV)
  - Floods in North Vietnam (Box 11)
  - Foreign relations
  - Free World Aid
  - Geneva Agreements of, 1954
  - Geography
  - Government of South Vietnam
  - Government (GVN) speeches
  - Government structure
  - Government administration
  - Government administration (Box 12)
  - Government policy statements
  - Haiphong, general (Box 13)
  - Handicraft
  - Hanoi, general data
  - Hanoi on peace terms
  - Health and medicine
  - Health in DRV
  - Heavy industry (DRV)
  - Highways in South Vietnam
  - History of Vietnam since, 1954
  - History of Vietnam, general
  - History, heroes of Vietnam
  - Ho Chi Minh
    - General file
    - Former President (DRV)
    - Myth of
    - Speeches (Box 14)
  - Ho Van Bun, letter from
  - Honey, P. J., miscellaneous articles on DRV
  - Hue City, general information
  - Hue massacre ( Tet 1968)
  - Hungary
  - Index on North Vietnam (Intelligence Subject Code Extract) (Box 15)
  - India and Vietnam
  - Indochinese People's Summit Conference, (April 24-25 1970)
  - Industrialization in South Vietnam
  - Industry, labor
  - Infrastructure, Viet Cong
  - Intelligence, Viet Cong (Military Intelligence)
  - International Association of Democratic Lawyers
  - International Commission for Supervision and Control in Vietnam (I.C.C.) Report, June 2, 1962
  - International Opinion and Vietnam
  - Interviews
    - Col. Dac
    - Dang Tan (MD)
    - Dieu
    - Hoang Minh Tan and Nguyen Duy Hung
    - Hoang Van Thanh
    - Huynh Bon
    - Lai Van Cu
    - Le Vinh Can
    - Le Xuan Chuyen
    - Ngo Dinh Nhu (Mme.)
    - Nguyen Huu Tho
    - Nguyen Duy Hung, see Hoang Minh Tan
    - Nguyen Luong Nhon (aka Viet Hung; aka Tu Tung)
    - Nguyen Ngoc Mai (Box 16)
    - Nguyen Thanh Binh
    - Nguyen Trong Xuan
    - Nguyen Van An
    - Nguyen Van Ba
    - Nguyen Thi Ngoc Bong (Mrs.)
    - Nguyen Van Chan
    - Nguyen Van Phe
    - Pham Thanh Tai
    - Phan Van Xuong
    - Phan Viet Dung
    - Tran Thi Ho Le
    - Tran Van Dac (1-3) (Box 17)
    - Tran Van Dung
    - Trieu Van Nghia
    - Tuong
    - Vu Van Bay
  - Interviews and conversations in Tan An, miscellaneous Joint U.S. Public Affairs Office, Saigon (JUSPAO)
    - Wireless Bulletin
    - Planning Office and Staff Studies
  - Labor movement in South Vietnam (Box 18)
  - Land reform, DRV, Bloodbath Controversy (Porter, Chi, etc.)
  - Land reform in South Vietnam
  - Language
  - Laos
  - Laos operation, 1971
  - Law in South Vietnam, legal system, constitution, etc. (Box 19)
  - Leadership in South Vietnam
  - Leadership of South Vietnam
  - Legality of U.S. involvement in Cambodia
  - Letters (selected) written by defected Vietnamese soldiers, 1968
  - Literature, drama, music
  - Living conditions in DRV
  - Lodge, Henry Cabot
  - Logistics, NVN File (and Ho Chi Minh Trail)
  - Luce, Donald
  - Magazine and academic articles (Box 20)
  - Martial Law
  - Military aid to South Vietnam
  - Military, electronic warfare in Vietnam
  - Military, Pre-1961
  - Military, 1962-1972
  - Military, Offensive, April 1972
  - Ministry of Information, Vietnam (Box 21)
  - Mission in Charge of Liaison (ML)
  - Montagnards
  - Moral case for U.S. involvement in Cambodia
  - My Lai massacre
  - National Assembly (SVN) (Box 22)
  - National Front for Liberation (NLF)
    - Congresses, (1968)
    - Policy
    - Policy statements
    - Budget and fiscal
    - Population controls and security
    - Relationship with Hanoi
    - Standing and Central Committee meetings
    - Structure
  - National Student Committee for Victory in Vietnam
  - Negotiations
  - Neutralism, Vietnam (Box 23)
  - Newspaper correspondents' reports
  - Ngo Dinh Diem
    - General information
    - Opposition to
    - Speeches
  - Ngo Dinh Nhu, Madam
  - Nguyen Cao Ky
  - North Korea
  - North Vietnam (Box 24)
  - North Vietnamese Army, role in South Vietnam
  - Opium growing in North Vietnam
  - Outer Mongolia
  - Pacification
  - Pacification in South Vietnam
  - Peace proposals, DRV
  - Peasants
  - People's Revolutionary Party (PRP), general description
  - PRP Youth League/Youth Vanguard
  - Personalism
  - Phoenix Program against Viet Cong Infrastructure (VCI)
  - Pike, Douglas, miscellaneous articles
  - Photographs, captured VC
  - Poland
  - Political (Box 25)
  - Political parties, SVN (Dai Viet)
  - Postal system in North Vietnam
  - Prisoners of war
    - General
    - Hanoi, 1972
    - Hanoi claims War Criminals
    - NVA (DRV File)
    - Viet Cong
    - VN war file
  - POW-MIA (Missing in Action) organization in U.S.
  - Prisons, South Vietnam (Box 26)
  - Proselyting (Binh Ven)
  - Public health in South Vietnam
  - Refugees in South Vietnam
  - Refugees
  - Regional Conference
  - Religion in South Vietnam
  - Revolutionary development
  - Revolutionary development in South Vietnam
  - Rice production in South Vietnam
  - Rumania
  - Saigon, general information (Box 27)
  - SEATO (Southeast Asia Treaty Organization)
  - Sappers
  - Security in South Vietnam
  - Security, Viet Cong
  - Sihanouk
  - Sino-Soviet confrontation
  - Sino-Soviet Relations
    - Border clashes and talks
    - Current military situation
    - War preparations (Box 28)
    - Possible military strategy in case of war
  - Solgans, (May Day)
  - South Vietnam, Miscellaneous
  - Strategic hamlets
  - Struggle Movement (Dich Van)
  - Students, martyrs
  - Tactics of VC
  - Tax collection, VC
  - Terrorism (Box 29)
    - General
    - VC incidents (Saigon Press Releases)
    - Viet Cong (Incident Reports)
    - Viet Cong/North Vietnamese Army (NVA)
  - Tet Offensive, 1968
  - Thailand, insurgency
  - Thompson, Sir Robert, TV interview with
  - Thompson, Sir Robert (Miscellaneous)
  - Tourism in Vietnam (Box 30)
  - Transportation, SVN
  - United Nations and related agencies
  - U.S. Government, 1969 assessment of Vietnam
  - U.S. Information Agency (U.S.I.A.), Vietnam Roundup
  - U.S. Mission in Vietnam, press playbacks and releases
  - U.S. Forces. Psychological Operations (U.S. PSYOPS), Interrogation Report. Source Nguyen-Viet.
  - U.S.S.R. (Union of Soviet Socialist Republics) (Box 31)
  - Veterans in Vietnam
  - Viet Cong, miscellaneous data
  - Viet Cong tunnels
  - Vietnam Alliance of National, Democratic, and Peace Forces
  - Vietnam Veterans for a Just Peace
  - Vietnamese communist leadership
  - Vietnamese scouting program
  - Vietnamization
  - Village (South Vietnamese) (Box 32)
  - VIVA (Victory in Vietnam Association)
  - Wars of National Liberation
  - Women in South Vietnam
  - Women cadres
  - Women organizations
  - Workers/Liberation Laborers' Association
  - Young Americans for Freedom
  - Youth, Vietnamese students in U.S.
  - Youth in South Vietnam
  - Youth organizations, South Vietnam
  - Miscellaneous
- Miscellany.
  - Clippings. (Box 32)
- Increment, December, 1977 (Box 33)
- Speeches and Writings, 1968-1972
  - Myths of The Vietnam War, The Pentagon Papers Reconsidered, photocopy of typewritten draft of article for Southeast Asian Perspectives., 1972 (Box 33)
  - Vietnam, A Corrective Essay, copy of published article., 1970
  - Vietnam, A Documented Analysis of The Backgrounds, Issues, and Alternatives, typewritten draft of unpublished book., 1968
- Subject File, 1966-1972
  - Agicultural Cooperatives, 1969 (Box 34)
  - Central Office For South Vietnam, 1969
  - Do, Tran, General, 1966-67
  - Joint United States Public Affairs Office, Saigon, Viet-Nam, Documents and Research Notes; Nos. 1-76, October 1967-April, 1970
  - Joint United States Public Affairs Office, Saigon, Viet-Nam, Documents and Research Notes; Nos. 77-95, June, 1970-March, 1971 (Box 35)
  - Joint United States Public Affairs Office, Saigon, Viet-Nam, Documents and Research Notes; Nos. 96-98, 101, 103, 106, July, 1971-June, 1972 (Box 36)
  - Long An Province Survey, 1966
  - Pike, Douglas, Viet Cong Strategy of Terror, n.d.
  - Political Alignment of Vietnamese Nationalists, 1949
  - Viet-Cong Infrastructure, The, 1970 (Box 37)
  - Vietnamese Conflict, 1961-1975
    - Bibliography
    - Diplomatic History
    - Military Operations
  - Who's Who In Vietnam, Vietnam Press, 1967
  - Miscellaneous note cards prepared for research and publication. (Box 38)
- Miscellany.
  - Clippings. (Box 39)
- Photographs., (235 photos / 74 negatives (on 10 filmstrips) (17 envelopes, 1 album) (Box Envelopes A-U)
  - 10 photos pertaining to the Vietnamese Scouting Program., undated (Folder A)
  - 13 photos relating to higher education in Vietnam., undated (Folder B)
  - 10 photos pertaining to agriculture (Five Year Plan) in South Vietnam., undated (Folder C)
  - 14 photos of the Armed Forces of the Republic of Vietnam, depicting training activities, boats, etc., undated (Folder D)
  - 21 photos pertaining to public health in Vietnam, depicting training of nurses and health services at hospitals, at the recuperation center of the "Save the Children Fund," dispensaries, etc., undated (Folder E)
  - 34 very small prints (on 5 filmstrips) of a South Vietnamese village. (17 different photos)., undated (Folder F)
  - 11 photos pertaining to South Vietnam Supreme Court elections., undated (Folder G)
  - 74 photos (27 in album), 40 negatives (on 5 filmstrips) depicting scenes in "Hue" after the Viet Cong "Tet" - offensive in 1968; also 1 tape cassette with interviews taken near the graveyard in "Hue" on a field trip in 1971. (Folder H-L)
  - 2 photos of Nguyen-Ngoc-Tho., undated (Folder M)
  - 1 photo depicting a Catholic procession in the liberated area of Ben Tre province (Nam Bo)., undated (Folder N)
  - 1 photo of two youngsters of the communist Dong Nai Regiment (K-3) who defected to the government side., undated (Folder O)
  - 11 photos of refugees in South Vietnam., undated (Folder P)
  - 1 photo of R.F. Turner with Vietnamese Children., undated (Folder Q)
  - 6 photos of a farewell party at the joint U.S. Public Affairs Office, Saigon (JUSPAO), depicting Major Joseph J. Heinlein, Deputy Chief for operations, and others., undated (Folder R)
  - 4 miscellaneous unidentified photos., undated (Folder S)
  - 6 photos of civilian prisoners in North Vietnam and 1 flier published by the National Student Coordinating Committee for Freedom in Vietnam and Southeast Asia., undated (Folder T)
  - 47 photographs showing various scenes of the National Liberation Front training with automatic weapons, undergoing indoctrination, preparing booby-traps, and posing with personalities. Plus three unidentified photographs of life in South Vietnam., undated (Folder U)
- Increment, December 1977. (Box 33. - 39.)
- Additional increment (Box 40-54)
- Sound recordings
  - Interviews taken near the graveyard in 'Hue' on a field trip in 1971, 12-14 April 1971; 1 sound cassette (Cassette-cabinet Cassette cabinet)
    Access
    Use copy reference number: 74040_a_0010360
    Part 1: 12 April 1971 Part 2: 14 April 1971